A little pause... and we are back.
A little pause...
and we are back.
A little pause... and we are back.
Why didn't somebody wake me up?
Where is everybody?
Where'd they all go?
Oh, Naruto.
Your sensei wanted to let you rest.
You got the day off.
I knew it!
They ditched me!
See ya!
Hold on!
What the heck is this?
What happened?
Someone was here!
Someone got to them!
Could it be?
Inari!
Could you give me a hand here?
I'll be right there!
It's mist.
Sasuke!
Sakura!
Get ready!
I knew he was still alive.
He just couldn't wait for round two.
Kakashi-sensei, it's Zabuza, isn't it?
This is his hidden mist jutsu!
Sorry I kept you waiting, Kakashi.
I see you've still got those brats with
you.
That one's still trembling.
Pitiful.
I'm trembling with... excitement.
Go on, Sasuke.
I can see it!
Ooh!
Ooh, so you could see they were water
clones, huh?
The brat's improving.
Looks like you've got a rival,
Haku.
So it seems.
They could have woken me up!
Well, well.
So I had it right.
It was all an act.
An act?
With a cute little mask.
Huh?
Big phony.
So I guess all that about
being a tracker ninja
protecting his village
was just a bunch of bull.
They look pretty chummy to me.
I'd say they've been pulling scams like
that for a long time.
He's got some nerve facing us again after
pulling that one.
And hiding behind a mask?
Who does he think he's fooling?
Speak for yourself, Sensei.
That's it.
I'm taking him out.
Who does he think he's fooling?
Hiding behind that mask like some sort of
clown?
Sasuke!
You're so cool!
Wait a second.
Didn't I just say that?
She'll never change.
He's impressive.
Hmph.
Even though they were
just one tenth the strength of
the original water clone
jutsu, he did destroy them all.
That move still gave us the first
advantage.
Now use it.
Right.
So you're Tazuna's daughter, huh?
Too bad.
You'll have to come with us, now.
Don't move!
Shall we grab this one, too?
No.
Gato asked for just one hostage.
Hostage!
Alright.
Then let's waste them!
Wait!
Please don't hurt my son.
I'm begging you, he's just a boy.
I'll do... anything.
Just please don't hurt him.
Looks like your mom came through for you,
kid.
Lucky.
What a waste.
I was in the mood to cut something.
Give it a rest.
You already drew blood today.
Let's get her out of here.
I'm sorry, mom!
I'm sorry!
What... could I do?
I'm too weak to protect you!
I'm scared.
I don't want to die!
Coward!
Listen to yourself, whining and
complaining like some sorry little victim!
You can whimper all day, for all I care!
You're just a coward!
If you really care about something,
protect it.
Even if you have to put your life on the
line.
Protect it.
With both arms.
Inari...
Father!
We're gonna treat you just fine, so
don't you worry your pretty little head.
Come on, keep walking.
Stop!
Well, well, if it ain't the little tough
guy.
Inari!
How cute.
You've come to save your mommy.
You'd better get away from my mom!
Inari, no!
This kid's a little short on brains,
don't you think?
Take him down.
If you hurt him, I swear I'll...
Shut up.
Take him down.
Inari...
A substitution, Jutsu.
The woman!
She's gone!
Sorry I'm a little late.
Huh?
Who's that?
You know, heroes usually show up at the
last minute.
Naruto, it's you!
Who else?
Inari?
You did great.
Huh?
When you charged, they forgot about your
mom for a minute.
That gave me the chance to use a cool
Jutsu to get her away from them.
Naruto...
How did you know these samurai guys were
coming here?
Uh... In the forest, I found a boar that
had been attacked.
And the trees were all cut up,
too.
Like someone had been practicing with a
sword or something.
The cuts led back toward the house.
So I followed them here.
That was really smart.
Blah blah.
It's one of those puny ninja brats Tazuna
hired.
Get him.
Yeah.
They're coming!
Try something else!
I did.
You did it!
Hey, by the way, sorry about yesterday.
Huh?
Calling you a coward was pretty mean,
I guess.
Anyway, it's not true, you know.
Because you were really brave.
Huh?
Darn it!
I promised myself I wouldn't cry anymore!
You're gonna make fun of me again and call
me a baby!
But I can't stop!
You're happy.
What's wrong with that?
Hehehehehe.
Huh?
When you're happy, it's okay to cry.
Really, it is.
Naruto!
Hehehehehe.
Okay, I can leave you in charge of things
now, right?
Yeah.
Good.
You can call me Tazuna.
Then I'm going over to the bridge!
It's not easy being a hero!
It's tough!
Believe it!
So... he can keep up with Haku's speed,
huh?
Sakura, cover Tazuna and stay close to me.
Let Sasuke handle this.
We want the bridge builder, not you.
If you back down, I won't have to kill
you.
Save it.
You're making a mistake.
You won't be able to keep up with my
speed.
I've gained two key advantages.
Yeah?
What are they?
First, we're surrounded by water.
Second, I've blocked one of your hands.
Therefore, you only have one free hand to
defend yourself.
Hand signs with a single hand?
I've never seen that before.
Secret jutsu.
A thousand needles of death.
He doesn't want to kill the kid.
Remember the training.
Focus.
Summon my chakra at once.
He vanished.
You're not as fast as you think.
It's not possible.
No one's faster than Haku.
Thought you were quicker, huh?
Now what else are you wrong about?
You made a big mistake insulting these
ninja and calling them brats.
That's just guaranteed to bring out
Sasuke's attitude.
And he's the best young fighter of the
Hidden Leaf Village.
And Sakura here is our sharpest mind.
And last but not
least, our number one
hyperactive knucklehead
ninja is Naruto Uzumaki.
Haku, if we keep going like this,
we'll be the victims instead of them.
Get on with it.
Right.
What's that?
I'm sorry it's come to this.
The air.
So cold.
Secret jutsu.
Let's do this one!
Mm...
Maybe.
Well, it's gonna be Tracer!
I'm ready.
If you enter this fight, you fight me.
Now, we'll begin.
And I'll show you what speed really means.
Just try to help him, and I'll kill the
other two in a heartbeat.
I'm sorry.
I can't stay with you.
Forgive me.
I understand.
Go now.
Take this!
Ugh...
What a fool.
Such a show-off.
Number one, hyperactive knucklehead ninja.
Naruto Uzumaki!
It's here!
Yeah!
Believe it!
Naruto!
You know how in stories
the hero usually shows
up at the last minute
and then kicks butt?
Well, that's what I'm gonna do right now!
Believe it!
This brat again.
What an idiot.
If he'd have stayed hidden, he could have
been so much more effective.
That boy... Alright!
You're history!
I'll clone Jutsu!
No!
Haku, what are you doing?
Zabuza, this boy... let me fight him my
own way.
Please.
So you want me to leave this to you.
Is that it, Haku?
As usual, you're too soft.
Forgive me.
Soft?
He's right.
Look at these wounds.
He cut me up with his needles,
yet he didn't hit a single vital spot.
Why?
It's impossible.
Naruto can't match this kid.
I've got to... Don't
even think about it.
You know the score, Kakashi.
If you go after Haku, I go after the
bridge builder.
He's got me.
Relax, Kakashi.
Sit back and enjoy the show.
Let's see how they do.
One on one.
That mask!
And your bogus story!
You were with Zabuza all along!
You think you can get away with a stunt
like that?
I'm sorry.
Deceiving your opponent?
Catching them off guard?
That is the art of the shinobi.
Please don't take it personally.
And while you're jabbering, I'll catch you
off guard!
I haven't forgotten about you.
Not for an instant.
Sasuke?
Some warriors accept defeat gracefully.
They know when they are beaten.
Others do not.
So be it.
Let us finish our battle then.
To the death!
Wha... Hey, where are you going?
It's alright, Naruto.
We'll have our fight next.
Here he comes!
The real one is over there.
I'm behind you.
He transported himself!
In an instant!
How?
What kind of jutsu is this?
Could it be... he has clones hiding in the
mirrors?
All throwing needles at the same time?
No, they're too fast for that.
I can't even see where they're coming
from!
And if it was just a clone jutsu... then
he wouldn't need them.
In the ice mirrors...
If I attack him from here, and Naruto hits
him from the outside... we can do it.
Hey!
I snuck in here to save you!
Pretty cool move, huh, Sasuke?
You are a complete loser!
You're a shinobi!
Think carefully before you move!
What the heck's your problem?
You should thank me for coming in here to
help you!
Naruto, if we're both
inside here... Forget it!
I've had it with your mistakes!
And I've had it with your attitude!
Believe it!
Naruto's building a solid reputation as
the most clueless ninja in history.
The more he helps, the worse things get.
That's it!
I'm gonna destroy these mirrors right now!
Fire style!
Hey, what attack are you using?
These mirrors are made of ice,
so how do you destroy ice?
Figure it out!
Fireball jutsu!
That didn't do anything at all!
You'll need much more heat than that to
melt this ice.
Where is he?
Where's the needle attack coming at us
from?
Are they clones?
We've gotta find the real one!
Which one is it?
Look into every mirror as hard as you
like.
You will never learn the secret.
Oh yeah?
Shadow Cloth Jutsu!
No!
Don't!
You've got a hundred mirrors!
Then a hundred of me will smash them all!
Then I'll find where you really are!
Jutsu!
These mirrors only reflect my image, allowing
me to transport myself at light speed.
Through my eyes, you appear to be moving
in slow motion.
It's a Kekei Genkai!
Kekei Genkai?
What is it?
It's like my Sharingan.
You can't learn it.
It has to be in your blood.
In your genetic code passed down from
generation to generation within a single clan.
Even I can't copy that Jutsu.
I couldn't break through!
So what?
He's not gonna stop me!
I'm not giving up and I'm not gonna lose
here!
Cause I have a dream and no one's gonna
take it away from me!
Someday I'll be respected in my village!
That's my dream!
To be the greatest Hokage!
Dreams...
It was not my desire to be a Shinobi.
It's painful.
I don't want to kill you.
But if you advance, I will have no choice.
Then I will kill the kindness in my own
heart and fully embrace the Shinobi way.
And there will be no mercy.
No turning back.
This bridge will be the battlefield where
our dreams collide.
Now I must fight for my dream.
Just as you fight for yours.
Please do not blame me.
I fight for someone who is precious to me.
I live for him.
And I face death for him.
So that his dream may become reality.
That is my dream.
And for the sake of
that dream, if I must,
I will act as a Shinobi
and take your lives.
Sasuke!
Naruto!
Take this guy out!
You can do it!
Don't, Sakura.
Don't push them.
Huh?
Even if they somehow
found a way to overcome the
Mirojutsu, they still
couldn't defeat this ninja.
But how can you be so sure?
They have the desire to win.
But they don't have the instinct to kill.
Exactly.
Your village has become complacent.
Your trainees never learn the most
important lesson of all.
To kill the feelings in their own hearts.
To crush an opponent mercilessly.
To destroy with no emotion or regret.
It's me or Zabuza here and now.
I'll have to do this the hard way.
Shot and gun.
You're no fun, Kakashi.
Using the same old trick.
If it's just an old trick, why did you
just stop me?
Let your opponent see your jutsu too many
times.
And he'll find a way to use it against
you.
Then count yourself lucky.
You're the only man alive who's seen my
Sharingan twice.
Show's over.
There won't be a third time.
Even if you did defeat me, you'd have no
chance against Haku.
When I found him, he was just a street
kid.
But I trained him in the most advanced
ninja techniques.
...
... ...
I taught him everything I know.
Plus, he had special abilities that he
refined on his own.
In the end, his power surpassed even mine.
His bloodline trait, the Kekkei Genkai,
cannot be defeated by anyone.
I've created a tool that can destroy
anything that stands in my way.
He's the ultimate.
A battle tool of destruction.
Are you finished bragging?
You're starting to put me to sleep.
Let's finish this.
Now!
Fine.
But there's one more thing you should
know.
A little more bragging, as you say.
I know you need me, Zabuza.
I'll finish them off quickly.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
He just won't give up.
... ...
... ... ... ...
He read my movements.
But that's not possible.
Got him that time.
I'm starting to get the timing.
I was so close, but I couldn't quite get
to him.
Naruto, can you do it again?
Huh?
Of course!
Nothing can stop me!
Believe it!
He doesn't want to show it, but he's
exhausted.
The Shadow Clone Jutsu uses up so much
chakra.
But thanks to him, I figured it out.
The human eye cannot track my movements.
It must have been a coincidence.
Naruto!
Run for it!
Get out of here and attack from the
outside!
Hurry!
Uh, all right!
You got it!
You cannot escape!
You think you can keep me here?
Forget it!
That's it!
Fire Style!
Fireball Jutsu!
I couldn't get past him!
That was good, Naruto!
Huh?
One more time?
Yeah!
Let's do it!
There must be a limit to his chakra,
too.
I can feel him slowing down.
No more games.
I need to stop this now!
This time you'll stay down!
I've been waiting to see
the look on your face when
you realize your Sharingan
has become worthless.
You once said the same jutsu won't work on
me twice.
Well, now I'm telling you that.
Huh?
Ninja Art.
Hidden Mist Jutsu.
This is it.
Sakura, stay with Tazuna.
Oh, Sakura.
Follow my lead, Mr. Tazuna, and whatever
happens, stay close!
All right.
I'll stay right behind you.
It's the Hidden Mist Jutsu.
But this mist is too thick even for
Zabuza.
How can he fight in it?
Very skillful.
As I'd expect from Kakashi, the Sharingan
warrior.
His eyes are closed.
But next time you see me will be the last
time you see anything.
Without your Sharingan, you're nothing.
What?
You wanted me to believe you could see
through anything.
Even through time.
But your prediction was wrong.
I'm still alive.
So you're a fraud, Kakashi.
You can't read the future, and you can't
read me.
Now that I know this, a very simple plan
can defeat you.
First, neutralize your piercing eye with
Zero Visibility Mist.
Ah!
By keeping my own eyes closed.
You can't bore into my mind if you can't
look into my eyes.
Brilliant.
Except with your eyes closed, you can't
see me either.
Have you forgotten who I am, Kakashi?
I'm the demon of the Hidden Mist,
master of the Silent Kill.
I can take you out by sound alone.
It's been a long time since I faced anyone
this tough.
And Sasuke and Naruto.
I don't know if they can hold out.
Stay calm.
Think.
Where will he strike?
The bridge builder!
Too late!
.
That scream... that was Sakura.
What's happening to her?
Where's Kakashi?
Sakura... she's in trouble.
Naruto, are you able to get up?
Try not to use any more chakra.
That's only going to help him now.
I know, Sasuke.
I know.
We can't go on like this.
He's blocking every move we make.
I've got to find a way to outmaneuver him.
My eyes have adjusted to his movements.
Looking for a counterattack?
I'll save you the trouble.
What?
Get up, loser!
We've got to team up!
I'm aiming at his vital spots now.
But I can't get a direct hit.
I know what we have to do.
Believe it, Sasuke!
It's not just luck.
He's fighting to protect his friend.
That's why he's so determined.
But he can't possibly see the needles
coming.
And yet, he's tracking them.
Somehow.
Whatever he's doing, I've got to stop him
now.
He disappeared!
Where'd he go?
How could he just vanish?
Naruto, you'd better not pass out again.
Come on, let's go!
I can't keep protecting you like this!
Well, then don't!
I never asked for your help!
You can't revive him.
He's reached his limits.
Your attacks are very skillful.
But you've reached your limits as well.
Stay calm.
Focus.
He saw every move.
But... there's no way he could do that.
Impossible.
Those eyes.
The Shotting Gun.
Your... It's not complete.
But I could see through his deceptions.
So, even now, his eyes are tracking me.
I can't target him directly.
He'll just block a frontal attack.
So I'll have to throw him off guard by
attacking his partner.
Then I'll destroy him.
What?
I've got to stop him!
You let your concern for those little
punks' safety cloud your mind,
adding further to the fog that already
hinders your Shotting Gun.
Your eyes are sharp, Kakashi.
But not sharp enough to read my moves.
Not anymore.
Come on, Kakashi.
I want this to be fun.
I want to enjoy myself as I exact my
revenge.
As for those brats... don't worry.
They're at Haku's mercy.
No, they're breathing their last breaths.
Right now.
Relax.
You'll have plenty of time
to weep out an apology for
failing those brats when
you see them in the next life.
Hahahaha!
He said Sasuke... will die!
No, I won't believe that!
I have faith in him!
Sasuke will beat them to a pulp!
Cha!
And that masked kid?
They'll make him wish that he was never
born!
I can't lose Sasuke!
Anyone who tries to take him from me will
pay for it!
I... and Naruto, either!
Exactly.
I... I believe in their abilities.
I have faith in them.
Naruto, the number one hyperactive
knucklehead ninja.
And Sasuke, heir to the most powerful clan
in the Hidden Leaf Village.
You mean... Yes.
His full name is Sasuke Uchiha.
The Kekkei Genkai is his birthright.
I heard that one young ninja survived the
tragedy of the Uchiha clan.
No wonder he advances so quickly.
But... so does Haku.
No one can match him.
No one has ever stopped his secret jutsu.
Even the most skilled Jonin fall before
him.
Just as you will fall before me!
Right now!
He's right.
It's time to end this.
But he is the one who will fall!
You always... get in the way, Naruto.
It never fails.
You beat him, Sasuke!
You should see the look on your face.
You... you look like a total loser.
Why... why did you... save me?
Why did you do it?
I don't know why.
I... I just did.
And my future dream is... to be the
greatest Hokage!
Then the whole village
will stop disrespecting
me and start treating
me like I'm somebody!
Get up, loser!
We climbed all the way to the top!
I want some more!
Why are they so obsessed with him?
Yes.
Now it's mine.
And Sasuke was so cool!
Like he'd done this a thousand times!
Sasuke!
You... I hated you.
Then why?
It doesn't make any sense.
Why did you... protect me?
I don't know.
My body just moved.
There was no time to think.
I... I... I'm...
I'm... a loser!
Sasuke!
He... he's still out there...
My brother... I promised myself...
I'd... stay alive... until... I killed
him.
Naruto, don't let... your dream die.
He was a true ninja, worthy of honor.
Is this the first time you have seen a
friend die in battle?
This is part of what it means to be a
ninja.
Shut up!
I'm gonna kill you!
What is this chakra?
Chakra cannot be seen, yet it's clearly
visible.
It's something ghastly.
I can feel the wrath, the bloodlust,
like evil itself.
His hand is healing, and changing.
This boy, what is he?
There's no way.
What is this energy?
Something foul.
Kakashi?
No... It's too powerful, even for him!
Where is it coming from?
Now you have seen all.
One more time... Makes a good
use of this powerful energy...
Must spend him a day in jail.
Hang in there... MISCHIEVES!
Bloodlust in his eyes.
This is no longer a child.
His chakra grows stronger every second.
I must strike now!
Now!
Impossible!
Those eyes!
Could it be?
The seal has been broken?
No.
It's been loosened,
and a glimmer of the
Nine-Tailed Fox's chakra
has slipped through.
But the seal still holds.
Good.
Then maybe we still have a chance.
Just maybe.
Zabuza, I don't mean to spoil your fun.
I know how you like to stretch these
things out.
But how about we put an end to this now?
Come on, what do you say?
We're both busy people.
Tempting.
I'm curious to see how you intend to back
up such brave words.
Show me, Kakashi!
I can't!
His energy is too strong!
That's no excuse.
I are kimchi, but it's over.
I'm still a child!
Zabuza... I am no match for this boy.
Boy...
Master... I have failed.
So, that guy in the woods, that was you?
Why do you not strike?
Did you not just vow to avenge your
comrade's death by killing me?
Or was that vow just empty words?
And no, that won't do.
You're still holding back.
If that is all the strength you can put
into it, you will never keep your vow.
Perhaps he didn't mean as much to you as
you pretend.
Is there anyone who's important to you?
There is only one person who matters to
me.
And I live to protect and serve him.
That is my purpose.
To show mercy to those who oppose the one
you serve?
To allow his enemies to live, when you
could strike them down?
This is not compassion.
It is a betrayal of your life's very
purpose.
For what reason do you exist, then?
You're of use to no one.
Your life has no meaning.
It is mere existence.
Day after day of pain and struggle,
signifying nothing.
Yeah, well, speak for yourself!
Are you really that blind little one I am
speaking of myself?
This day has shown that I am no longer of
any use to Zabuza.
Zabuza?
Why that guy, anyway?
To devote your life to a rotten skunk who
doesn't know the meaning of the word honor?
If he's really the one
person that matters to you,
man, that's the sorriest
thing I've ever heard!
There were once others who mattered to me.
Long ago.
My father.
And my mother.
I was born in the land
of water, in a small
village where the snow
lies deep in the winter.
My parents were farmers and very poor.
Our life was hard, but we were content.
My parents were good to each other and
kind to me.
Yes, we were happy once.
But then everything changed.
Because of something that happened long
before I was even born, everything changed.
What do you mean?
What was it?
What happened?
It wasn't my doing.
It is in the blood.
Blood?
So what was it?
You said something happened that changed
everything!
It was... my father who changed.
He killed my mother and he almost killed
me.
After years of suffering the horrors of
civil war, the people of my land had come
to fear and hate anyone who carried the
Kekkei Genkai in their blood.
Kekkei Genkai?
The advanced bloodline trait of a clan.
Its jutsu and abilities passed down from
generation to generation.
Because of their unique abilities,
the clans were used as mercenaries.
They fought in many battles and were much
feared.
But when the wars were over, they were
despised and shunned by the people who
feared their presence would only bring
more war and misfortune.
So it was that after the wars
these clans went into hiding,
denying the bloodline trait
that flowed in their veins.
Concealing their unique abilities, knowing
that to be discovered meant certain death.
If you had searched that boy's memories,
I'm sure you would have found it there too.
The cruelty of people.
Their fear of things they don't
understand.
For years, my mother was successful in
hiding her bloodline trait.
She met and fell in love with a simple
farmer.
And they were married.
And after that, my mother
thought she would lead
a peaceful, ordinary life
to the end of her days.
Mama, look what I can do!
See what I made?
See?
Isn't it beautiful?
No!
You must never!
Do you hear?
Never!
You wicked, wicked child!
Mama!
What is it?
Stop!
Mama!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, my darling.
I'm sorry.
My father had seen.
And so he knew our secret, my mother's and
mine.
But please, don't.
You must not tell this to my mother.
And my mother must know it.
When I am born, you must show me your true
identity.
What is it?
Yes, I love you too!
A little pause...
and we are back.
When at last I was myself again,
I was no longer myself.
My father and mother
were gone, but I knew
that something else
had been taken from me.
My purpose.
In all the world, there was no one who
needed me.
I was... unnecessary.
Just like... me!
Why is it you're so determined to be
Hokage?
Because you want all
eyes in your village to
look on you and recognize
you as a great ninja.
You see, it is only
through the eyes of others
that our little lives
have any significance.
When there is no one
who sees you or will
even look at you, it's
as if you do not exist.
Then Zabuza came along and looked at me,
and his eyes were not full of hate or fear.
He did not shun me for my strangeness.
Indeed, my special powers were just what
he wanted.
He made me necessary again.
Little kid like you.
With no one to look after you,
you'll die a beggar's death.
Hey, you know what?
Your eyes remind me of mine.
Well, little one.
Will you stay here and die, or come with
me and be of some use?
Will you serve me and submit to my will in
all things?
Oh, I won't.
For that, I'm runny and I can't team up
with the other boys.
Then your special abilities belong to me
from this day forward.
I want to know more about the Puppets.
...I have a plan.
A little pause... and we are back.
Encouragement.
I do not need these things, nor should you
expect them from me.
I understand.
I am yours, Zabuza.
I am only an instrument of your will.
Think of me as a weapon to be kept at your
side and used as you see fit.
Well said, child.
I have failed you, Zabuza.
I am like a weapon that has been broken
and is of no further use.
Naruto, kill me.
Ninja art summoning!
Earth-style fanged pursuit jutsu!
I don't know why you bother.
Of what use is your jutsu if you can't
even find me?
But I can find you.
Blindly falling into my trap.
You disappoint me, Kakashi.
I think you're right.
It is time to put an end to this.
I realized if I couldn't see you,
I'd have to smell you out.
But that was a summoning jutsu.
I was calling forth my ninja hounds.
They can track a scent anywhere.
When you attacked me, I let you get past
my guard.
I wanted you to cut me.
You see, it's the smell of my blood on
your blade that led them to you.
Surprised?
Looks like I wasn't the only one who was
blind.
Falling into my trap.
You disappoint me, Zabuza.
The mist is finally clearing.
And you know what I see?
Your death.
Talk, talk.
Do you mean to talk me to death?
In a way, yes.
Right now my hounds are just playing with
you.
But one word from me, and they'll tear you
apart.
Poor Zabuza.
See where your ambitions got you?
You were always pushing things too far.
Missing This is the failed Mizukage
assassination and your attempted coup d 'etat.
You were forced to flee
with the few followers you
had, your country's tracker
ninja hot on your heels.
You became a rogue ninja
whose name was quickly
known, even in the
village hidden in the leaves.
Now you're crazy enough to want to go back
and try it again.
But for that you need money,
and to get it you've stooped
so low as to be the hired
thug of a swine like Gato.
All right, Zabuza.
Enough talk.
Time to finish it.
But it won't be with Sharingan,
imitations of some other ninja's tricks.
No.
It's time I introduced you to... my own
jutsu.
Lightning Blade!
His chakra is so strong it's visible!
He holds it in his hands!
Your future's all used up, Zabuza.
Go on.
Finish it.
Kill me.
Why do you hesitate?
I thought you wanted to be a mighty
warrior.
That's not what it's about!
Do you really believe
that's all there is to it, just
fighting and killing till there's
only one man left standing?
There's a lot more to being shinobi than
that!
And there are other
ways of showing your
strength than just by
beating someone in battle!
I've had a feeling all along.
From the first moment we met in the woods.
We're a lot alike.
I'm sure you know what I mean.
I'm only sorry that it must be your hand
that is tainted with my unworthy blood.
Sure about this?
And you're positive that it's the only
way?
Yes.
The weird thing is, if we
met in another time and
place, I think that maybe
we could have been friends.
Yes.
That's right.
Hold fast to your dreams.
This is for Sasuke!
Because he also had a dream!
Thank you, Naruto.
Strike true.
At last, I think this blasted fog is
lifting.
Hm?
Look!
They're standing still!
Like they're squaring off!
Yeah?
I can't see a thing.
Which one of them's Kakashi-sensei?
One's moving!
Huh?
Sorry, Naruto.
Change of plan.
I'm not ready to die quite yet.
Ah!
Is this the end?
Yes!
And it was!
Not yet.
I'm starting to get excited.
Oof!
So, my future is all used up, huh?
Wrong again, Kakashi.
Uncle Gitchi!
Uncle Gitchi, hurry!
Come to the bridge with me!
We don't have to hide any longer!
If we all fight together, we can finally
take Kano down!
I know we can!
No, Inari.
I've given up fighting.
Fighting is for heroes.
Like your father.
You see what good it did him?
Isn't one dead hero enough?
What will more fighting bring us,
but more fallen heroes?
And more regrets?
No, Inari.
My heart is already full of enough
regrets... to last a lifetime.
All my life I've been a coward.
But now I know that crying and
hiding from things that we're afraid of...
doesn't make them go away!
... ...
...
Hurry!
Come to the bridge!
...
Our little Inari's become a man.
And you, dear?
Are you sure you want to send him off all
on his own?
... ...
...
Is anyone there?
Come to the bridge
with me and... ...
I have to go by myself because none of the
others will come with me!
...
I have no choice.
Stop this!
You're only a child!
What do you think you can do?
You're right.
I am just a kid.
But a kid who knows what it means to stand
and fight!
I'm my father's kid!
... ...
No!
Inari, wait!
Hm?
What?
Where'd he go?
... Huh?
Hey!
Ugh!
The fog's lifting!
Wait... is that him?
... ...
What?
I don't get it!
What the heck's going on here?
... ... ...
...
Isn't that... the young man in the mask?
He saved your worthless life... at the
cost of his own.
...
Well done, Haku.
... ...
Kakashi-sensei, watch out!
He'd hack right through the boy to take me
down?
... I knew I'd found a treasure
when I'd found you, boy!
You've not only given me my life,
but Kakashi's as well!
...
... ... ...
Not bad for having a corpse in your arms.
You'll pay for that!
No!
Stay out of this, Naruto!
...
Huh?
This is my battle.
Sabuza's mine.
... Naruto!
Over here!
Naruto!
...
Sakura... So you and
Sasuke are alright?
...
Um... What's wrong?
Where IS Sasuke, anyway?
...
... Ugh... ugh... no...
Kakashi!
I'd stay focused if I were you!
Let me take you to him, Sakura.
As long as we stay together, you won't be
disobeying your sensei's orders.
Thank you...
Sasuke...
His body's cold.
This isn't just one of his genjutsu
tricks, is it?
Go on.
You don't need to be brave on my account.
Go ahead and let your feelings out,
Sakura.
It's alright.
I was the best.
I aced every test at the academy.
The perfect student.
Did you know there are more than one
hundred principles of shinobi conduct?
I memorized every single one.
I used to love it when they tested us on
them.
Gave me a chance to show how smart I was.
I remember so clearly this one exam.
They asked us to explain the 25th
principle.
I got it right, of course.
A shinobi never shows his feelings.
No matter what the circumstance is.
Feelings are a weakness... that only cloud
his judgment and weaken his sense of duty.
Ugh... ugh... ugh...
To put such an unbearable burden on a
young girl's shoulders.
If that's the Shinobi way, you can have
it.
Why?
Why can't I keep up with him?
I'll split you in half!
Look at me!
Look at you.
You're falling apart.
I knew you didn't have what it takes for
the long haul.
What did you say?
You have no idea what real strength is.
Game over.
You lose.
Now both of your arms are useless.
What now?
You can't even make hand signs.
Hmm?
Did quite a job on you, didn't he,
Zabuza?
You look like yesterday's sashimi.
I must say, I'm disappointed.
Disappointed?
You're not.
Gato.
I don't understand.
What is all this?
Why are you here?
And who are these thugs you've brought
with you?
Hmm.
Well, you see, there's been a slight
change in plan.
According to the new plan, you die right
here on this bridge, Zabuza.
What?
That's right.
You're too expensive.
So I've decided to take you off the
payroll.
Of course.
Even these thugs I brought with me cost
something, so if you could manage to
slaughter a few of them before they take
you down, I'd appreciate it.
Think you can manage that, demon ninja of
the mist?
Look at you.
You look about as demonic as a wet kitten.
There are so many of them!
One rogue ninja was bad enough!
Well, well, Kakashi.
It would seem our fight is at an end.
Since I am no longer in Gato's employ,
Tazuna is safe.
We have no quarrel.
Yeah, I suppose you're right.
That reminds me... you little punk!
You grabbed me and nearly broke my arm!
I've been meaning to repay you for that!
I only wish he was alive to feel it.
Get away!
Get away from him, you scum!
Hey!
Stop!
Use your head!
Well, what about you, Zabuza?
You gonna let him do that?
Be quiet, you fool.
Haku's dead.
What does it matter?
What?
You mean you can just stand there and
watch him get treated like a dog?
You and Haku were together for years!
Doesn't that mean anything?
You don't understand the way of Shinobi.
I merely used him, just as Gato used me.
Huh?
Now it's over.
His usefulness is at an end.
The loss of his strength and skill,
yes.
That means something to me.
But the boy?
Nothing.
If you mean that, you're an even bigger
rat than I thought!
Okay, that's enough.
Calm down, Naruto.
He's not the enemy.
Not right now.
Ah!
Shut up!
Far as I'm concerned, he's enemy!
Enemy number one!
Why, you... you ungrateful... After
everything he did for you, Haku lived for you!
Is there... someone who's precious to you?
You were the most important thing in the
world to him!
For me, there is only
one person who matters,
and my purpose is to
protect and serve him.
And that purpose is what gives me my
strength.
And he meant nothing to you!
Nothing at all!
The way of Shinobi is very difficult for
me.
While he was sacrificing everything for
you, you never felt anything at all for him!
But I will do anything to see that his
dream is fulfilled.
Even become Shinobi if I must.
And if I become stronger, does that mean...
I'll become as cold-hearted as you are?
He threw his life away.
And for what?
For you and your dream?
I want only to make his dream come true.
That is my dream.
You never let him have a dream of his own.
But he didn't care.
I was happy.
And you just tossed him aside,
like he was nothing!
A broken tool!
Man, that's so wrong!
So wrong!
The End You talk too much.
Your words cut deep.
Deeper than any blade.
While he fought you... His
heart was breaking in two.
You see, Hakko was always too soft and too
kind.
He felt pain and sorrow, and now,
curse him, I feel them too.
And something else, I feel content that
this is the way it ends.
Well, Cat got your tongue.
Are you so surprised to discover that I'm
human?
Even Shinobi are human.
No matter how hard we try to escape that
simple fact, we always fail.
Well, at least, I have failed.
Boy, give me your kunai.
Ah...
Here.
That's enough of this!
Do it!
Take him down now!
He must be out of his mind!
One against all of us?
What's he thinking?
Come on!
Let me do something!
Hurry up!
Yeah!
There you are!
Get him!
Ah!
He's the devil!
You crazy fool!
If you're so eager to join your friend,
go ahead.
But you're not taking me!
Not this time!!!
I won't be joining Hakko.
Where he's gone I cannot follow.
Huh... Err...
Stay back!
We wouldn't be welcome where Haku's gone
to.
Hell's where we're going, Gato!
I can't think of a more fitting
destination for a demon ninja, can you?
I'm told there are many demons down there,
of all shapes and sizes.
Oh yes, I should fit right in.
You, on the other hand, Gato...
Well, I fear you're in for a long and very
painful eternity!
...
Haku...
So this is... goodbye... at last.
Not once did I ever thank you,
Haku.
Forgive me for that.
Don't turn away.
When you live like a warrior, this is how
it ends.
Where am I?
Am I alive?
Or... Sakura?
Can it be?
It is... Sakura.
It's hard to breathe with you on top of
me.
Sasuke!
Tatsuna!
He's alive!
Alive!
Sakura, that hurts!
Sasuke!
So things turned out right after all.
No!
No, what are you doing?
You shouldn't move!
How's Naruto?
And what happened to that guy in the mask?
Naruto's just fine.
But the... the one in the mask... he's
dead.
Dead?
But how?
Did Naruto do it?
Oh, I... I came in late.
I'm not sure what happened.
He was protecting Zabuza.
I had faith in you, Sasuke.
I knew you'd pull through.
You're too cool a guy to stay down for
long.
He never meant to... from the very
beginning.
Naruto!
Over here!
Look!
It's Sasuke!
He's alright!
But how?
While he fought you, his heart was
breaking in two.
You see, Haku was always too soft and too
kind.
I see.
Well, well.
Well, wonders never cease.
Amazing.
Hey!
Yoo-hoo!
Don't go getting too comfortable!
This party ain't over yet!
Who's gonna pay us now that Gato's gone?
No way we're gonna leave here
empty-handed!
So we'll just have to hit that village and
see what they've got for us!
Yeah!
Come on!
Not good.
Come on, Kakashi-sensei!
You must have a jutsu that can take care
of this bunch of losers!
Not right now.
I use too much of my chakra.
Get him, boys!
There's one little thing you're forgetting
about.
Before you set one foot in our village,
you'll have to go through all of us!
Inari!
Heroes usually show up at the last minute,
you know.
They've all come.
The whole village.
No way I'm gonna miss out on all the fun!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
I might have just enough chakra left to
help you out.
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Kakashi-style!
Okay.
Still want to fight?
No thanks!
Victory!
Sounds like it's over.
Yeah.
Kakashi, I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
Take me to him.
Before I go, I need to see him one last
time.
Sure.
Huh?
Impossible.
Snowing at this time of year?
Is it you, Haku?
Are you weeping?
Kakashi...
You
were always at my side.
The least I can do... is to
be beside you at the end.
How long are you going to make me stay at
the end of these counties?
I know it cannot be, but I wish I could go
to where you have gone.
Oh, I wish I could join you there.
Aku...
He told me where he came from,
it was always snowing.
All the time.
Of course.
His spirit was as pure as the snow.
You never know... Oh, Zabuza.
Maybe you will join him there.
Who's to say?
Is that really it, Kakashi-sensei?
Is that the ninja way?
To use and be used by people like tools?
Shinobi are all merely tools in the hands
of destiny.
No point in wondering whether it's right
or wrong.
It just is.
It's the same in the village itself.
Okay!
Hm?
I've just come to a decision.
From now on I'm finding my own Ninja Way.
A way that's straight and true and without
any regrets.
From now on I'm following the way of
Naruto!
We could never have finished the bridge
without you.
I can't tell you how much we're going to
miss you.
Do be careful.
Thank you for everything.
Now, now.
Don't get all choked up.
We'll come back and visit real soon.
You swear you will?
Of course.
You know, Inari, it's alright to cry if
you want.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Go for it.
Who says I want to cry?
Anyway, if there's nothing wrong with it,
then why don't you go on and cry?
No!
You first!
Forget it!
Boys can be so pathetic.
It was all his doing.
That boy made you stronger, Inari.
And you were... You, in turn,
made the rest of us stronger.
It was thanks to that boy.
We were able to build a bridge to a place
we'd never known.
A place where we found our courage.
A place to fulfill our dreams.
Say, speaking of the bridge, now that it's
finished, shouldn't we name it?
Yes, of course.
And I know just the name.
You do?
What?
We'll call it... The Great Naruto Bridge.
That's a very good name.
Haha!
As soon as we get back, I'm
gonna let Iruka-sensei fix me up
a whole mess of ramen to
celebrate a mission accomplished!
Oh!
And just wait till I tell Konohamaru about
all my adventures!
The kid's gonna worship me!
Hey!
Yeah?
Not you, Naruto.
Sasuke, when we get back, you wanna go out
and do something together?
I don't think so.
Thanks.
Oh.
Okay.
Sakura, I'd do something with you if you
want.
What?!
Hey, that was a private conversation!
It was something that Haku said to me.
He told me that when people are protecting
something that is truly precious to them,
that's when they can become genuinely
stronger.
I see.
And you agree with him, do you?
You bet.
After watching Haku with Sabuza,
I know he's right.
Hey, um, wait a second, Kakashi-sensei.
Tell me something.
What do you think?
You sure about that name, Tazuna?
It's a name that brought us good luck.
It'll do the same for the bridge.
I think this bridge will stand for a long,
long time.
Perhaps it will even be famous one day.
The name Naruto, known throughout the
world.
That would be something, wouldn't it?
Yeah.
Um, yeah, there's that name...
That God Two in Haku's Marriage
Umm... Never falling down.
My knee is too shaken, like I was twelve.
Sneaking out the classroom, by the back
door.
I'm alright, let me try some.
But I didn't care.
Waiting is wasting, for people like me.
Don't try, it's alright.
Don't cry, cause you're alright.
Don't try, this makes no sense.
Cause you will hate yourself in the end.
Don't try, to look so wise.
Don't cry, cause you're so alright.
Don't try, which fakes all fears.
Cause you will hate yourself in the end.
Don't cry, it looks so wise.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community